Ritik Singh

Address- 8197/7, Multani Dhanda, Paharganj,

New-Delhi (110055)

Contact- (+91) 9672828958

Email- ritik.singh.2802@gmail.com

LinkedIn- <u>Ritik Singh - Community Member -</u> LinkedIn India

GitHub- <u>ritiksingh29 (RITIK SINGH)</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

OBJECTIVE:

To secure a position as a machine learning and Data-Science Intern, leveraging my skills and experience to enhance my capabilities and learn new tech.

DESCRIPTION:

I am a skilled and motivated individual with a strong background in Software Engineer, Machine Learning, and Web Development. Throughout my academic and professional career, I have developed a deep understanding of the potential of Data Analytics and Artificial and have worked on several projects that demonstrate my expertise in this area.

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science Engineering [2020-2024]

Guru Govind Singh Indraprastha University, New Delhi [CGPA – 9.204, till 5th semester]

Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Data Structures and Algorithms, Object-Oriented Programming, Software Engineering, Artificial Intelligence, Operating Systems, Database Management Systems.

Senior Secondary School (12th std)

Central Board of Secondary Education [2019]

Gyan Bharti Residential Complex, Bodhgaya, Bihar

Percentage - 84.8%

Secondary education (10th std)

Central Board of Secondary Education [2017]

D.A.V Public School, Ghaziabad

CGPA - 9.8

EXPERIENCE:

Machine learning Industrial Training

Bharati Vidyapeeth's College of Engineering [September 2022 – October 2022, New Delhi]

- Developed a high-accuracy model for predicting the price of electric vehicles using Linear Regression, Random Forest, and Xgboost methods.
- Executed various libraries such as Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, and SkLearn.
- Achieved an accuracy of 91.04

Free-Lancing

GRIPA.IN-Web Development [July 2021 - September 2021, New Delhi]

- Assembled website's design and programmed the Front-End.
- Optimized Search Engine of the original-website.

NALFROST.COM-WordPress Development [February 2021 – April 2021, New Delhi]

- Designed and Constructed website layout.
- Enhanced Search Engine of this blogging-website.

SKILLS:

- C/C++ (Developing)
- Python (Fundamental)
- MYSQL (Advanced)
- HTML (Advanced)
- JAVASCRIP (Developing)
- REACT (Developing)
- BOOTSTRAP (Developing)
- CSS (Advanced)

- FIGMA (Developing)
- Git (Developing)
- Keras (Developing)
- ML (Advanced)
- OpenCV (Developing)
- TensorFlow (Developing)
- Scikit-Learn (Developing)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS:

Problem Solving, Adaptability, Teamwork, Leadership, Communication

PROJECTS:

Face Recognition Attendance System

- Directed a Model for recording Attendance with D-lib library and have High Accuracy.
- Embedded this model with user interactive website and captured images by using OpenCV and marked the attendance every time model detects people.
- Library Utilized- Numpy, Open-CV, OS Module, Face Recognition.

Skin Lesion Segmentation Project

- Designed a ml based stacked ensembled model of Unet and Resnet.
- Developed a Meta Model for enhancing and generating Skin Segmentation Images.
- Evaluated the images and generated their lesion segments.
- Technique Used Resnet Model, Unet Model, Stacked model with keras and TensorFlow.

Self-Learning Project

Ongoing [Executed Module - TensorFlow, Keras, and open-CV]

Dr_Plant: Introduced a web application using Machine-Learning models to detect plant diseases.

Facial Emotion Detection: Created a web application that detects human emotions using AI technology.

Self-Ai: A voice assistance capable of understanding, evaluating and providing response with the help of Chat-GPT

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE:

MICROSOFT LEARN STUDENT CHAPTER: [Core Member]

- Inspected events such as Access-A-Thon and Azure Payday with the entire team.
- Coordinated and Collaborated on a Git event.

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Academic Scholar from class 1st to class 10th.
- Finalist in the Hack-The-Crisis 2021.
- Ranked 399 out of 14000+ in CODECHEF STARTERS 96.

INTERESTS:

- Reading about the latest advancements in technology and Artificial Intelligence and Mythological text.
- Participating in Sport Events and Hackathons.
- Playing Football and Badminton.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Father's name: Jai Prakash Singh

Date of Birth: 28 February, 2001

Languages: English (Fluent), HINDI(Fluent)

REFERENCES:

Ms. SHILPA GUPTA DR. DEEPIKA KUMAR

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR, CSE HOD & Associate, DEPARTMENT OF

BVCOE, NEW DELHI COMPUTER SCIENCE

BVCOE, NEW DELHI Email: shilpa.gupta@bharatividyapeeth.edu

Email: <u>deepika.kumar@bharatividyapeeth.edu</u>